[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trienes tasa Advanced Training as you
all know I already published 56 YouTube
videos covering beginners intermediate
and advanced level
Concepts from couple of videos onwards
I've started teaching you the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter with
different types of obstacles and how can
we solve those obstacles by using trient
tasar so this is our obstacle 15 in
terms of realtime scenarios and this is
our lesson 57 in terms of overall
tricentis tasa
training please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank
you in this lesson I'm going to teach
you a realtime
scenario where you need to solve an
obstacle by using the methods while loop
and multiple interactions so now let us
see what is the obstacle in detail so
here is our obstacle again and again and
again this is categorized as medium
let's go for
it so what is the obstacle that you need
to
solve in order to complete this obstacle
you need to click the button labeled
click me after few clicks the button
will change to enough and then again
click that button to finish the exercise
so you need to click this click me
button
once second time third time fourth time
see
now after four clicks this Chang it to
enough now you click one more time now
your automation problem
solved so let me retry and this
button turns to enough not only for the
fifth time so it is dynamic it might
turn after one click or it might turn
after three clicks so it is dynamic so
again let me try one two see now this
button turned into enough after two but
after two clicks click now your
automation problem solved so how can we
solve this
for that let's go to
tasa and this is my trient tasa and this
is the obstacle folder where we are
scanning all our objects pertaining to
each obstacle so right click on this
folder click on scan and select
application now select
scan and here I would like to capture an
object of clickme right click me is the
button so this is the button I would
like to capture select this button and
then rename the module with the name of
your obstacle so let's go back here copy
the obstacle
name and then here paste the obstacle
name here and now we completed capturing
all the objects that are required to
solve the obstacle now save this
one and then close your xcam so let us
go back to
trentos so this is the the new obstacle
that we captured which has only one
object right so now let's now
concentrate on left side blue section
which is creation of test cases right
click on obstacles
folder create new test case and name
this as the same name that we copied
earlier double click on this now to
automate the test case simply drag the
module that we capture and drop onto
your test case so now what we need to do
we need
to click on this
button multiple times until the button
turns into enough so how can we achieve
this we can achieve this in different
methods but the appropriate method is
using while you can use if condition you
can use do conditions right but
in this case the appropriate method is
to use while condition okay so now what
I'm going to do here I'm going to right
click on this particular test case and
then I'm going to start
using this is my create while
statement and now I'm going to bring
this to the
Top This is my vo statement here what is
the condition
my condition is you have to click this
button until the button title is Click
me now I would like to copy
this same module or you can use the same
module drag here and drop on to the
condition right so what is the condition
my condition
is the inner text the inner text of this
particular button
equal to click me click me right so you
can see here now this is my capital
letters click me and here I would like
to verify this I want to verify if the
inner text of this button is Click me or
not so if this condition is meeting that
means if this condition met then I would
like to click on the button so that's
why again I would like to use the same
button under Loop that means once this
condition is satisfied it enters into
the loop what it is going to do it is
going to click on the
button so I'm clicking on the button
until this condition satisfies so what
it does it enters the loop it again
comes back it checks for the inner text
click me
then what happens again it clicks so
like that it keeps on repeating until
the inner text changes to enough if the
ner text changes to enough it comes out
but what we need to do once it turns
into enough again you need to click
that's why I'm adding another new Step
here basically I'm keeping the same old
step here and then I'm going to click
another time that's it so let me explain
one one more time okay so what we are
doing we are using the same object again
and again I'm using this object to
verify the condition if the inner text
is Click me and then I'm entering into
the
loop it clicks on the button again it
checks the condition if it meets again
it clicks again checks the condition if
it meets it again clicks so again comes
back if this does not meet the condition
then comes out of it and it clicks once
and then your test case is done so now
let us change the test case status or
work status as
completed and now let's save this
particular test case and let us run this
test case right click and run in
scratchbook
so it is clicking
once
twice three times see now enough is
changed it changed to enough and it
clicked one more time your automation
problem is solved let me again run again
okay let me run again to see if while
condition works correctly or not okay so
right click and run in
scratchbook so this time your button
might turn into enough within two clicks
or three clicks let's see if it
handles so it's clicked
once twice done so it turned in and then
it again clicked now your automation
problem is
solved so hope you all understand the
concept of solving the obstacle
by using while condition right so
anytime if you encounter this kind of
scenarios you need to use while
condition for interacting multiple times
with the same
object oh you all understand the concept
to solve an obstacle where you need to
click the button labeled click
me how many times we need to click that
we need to click few times the same
button until the button name changes to
enough we have used the concept of while
loop and multiple interactions to solve
this obstacle please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank you
oh
[Music]